Guide to the Department of Pharmacology, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Pharmacology, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1916-1943
RU 784
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(2 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, applications, recommendations, and general subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Department of Pharmacology at the Yale School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-E (YRG 27-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Medicine
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, applications, recommendations, and general subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Department of Pharmacology at the Yale School of Medicine
Pharmacology -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, circa 1916-1943; Accession 1991-A-092
  - Correspondence, 1929-1943
    - A, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - B, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - B: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - C, 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - C: Miscellaneous, 1929-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Callison, Dr. William E.: Personal, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - D, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - D: Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - E, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - F, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - F: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - G, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - G: Miscellaneous, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - H, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - H: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Harvard University Press, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Harvey, Dr. H. C., undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - I, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - J, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - K, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - I-J-K: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - L, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - L: Miscellaneous, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Lowe, M. Correspondence, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - M, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - M: Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Man, Dr. Evelyn B., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Means, Dr. J. H., 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - N, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - N: Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - National Safety Council, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - O, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - P, 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - P: Miscellaneous, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Photographic Collection, Correspondence regarding, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - R, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - R: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - S, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - S: Miscellaneous, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - T, 1939-1943 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - T: Miscellaneous, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - U-V, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - United States Senate, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - V: Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - W, 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - W: Miscellaneous, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Winternitz, Dr. M. C., 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - X-Y-Z, 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Yerkes, Robert M., 1931 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Administration, 1923-1945
    - Angell, James R. (President): Miscellaneous, 1931-1942 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Animals and Equipment, 1923-1936 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Apparatus, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Apparatus, Correspondence regarding, 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Applications, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Applications: Miscellaneous, 1928-1941 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Bills Paid: W. T. Salter, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Bishop, Miss L. G. (Executive Secretary), 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Blake, Dr. Francis G. (Office of the Dean), 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bree, Miss and Miss Clark, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Buck, Warren, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Bursary Students, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 64-65)
    - Chemicals, 1929-1943 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Childs, Jane Coffin, Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Childs, Jane Coffin, Fund #46: Statement, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Christian-Becker Co., 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Dasey, Miss: Registrar, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Fellowships and Awards, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Fluid Research Grants: Barbour, Goodman, Salter: Statements, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Gorrell and Gorell, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Graduate School, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Hoffman-Laroche, Inc., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - New Haven Hospital Supplies, 1938[?] (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Ostrander, Mr. H. G. (Office of the Treasurer), 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Pharmacology, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Pre-Clinical Committee, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Recommendations, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Reports to Provost and Dean, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Requests for Research Funds: Offers and Acceptances, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Reynolds Tobacco Company, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Rubicon Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Secretary's Office, Yale University, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Sterling Hall Extension, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Sterling Hall Extension: Specifications and Plans, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - This and That, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Visitors to Laboratory, 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Yale Medical Library: Selected Lists of Accessions, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Yale University, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Academic Matters, 1916-1941
    - Abstracts, Reviews, etc., 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Albert, Harry, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Clinical Congress, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Clinical Pharmacology, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Exams, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Experimental Pharmacology and Toxicology, 1930-1937 (Box 3, Folder 98-101)
    - Graduate Students, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Instructors in Pharmacology, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - McLean's Review on Phosphorous, undated (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Medical Students, 1933-1937, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 105-106)
    - Pharmacology 115a: Sumner B. Cotzin, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Pharmacology 115a: E. W. Fager, 1941[?] (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Pharmacology 115a: M. J. Fahrenbach, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Pharmacology 115a: Robert N. MacDonald, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Pharmacology 115a: Frank R. Valentine, Jr., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Pharmacology 115a: Donald E. Sargent, Robert Ebel, T. F. Scholz, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Reprints, 1935-1941 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Seminars, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Students in Second Pre-Clinical Year Pharmacology, 1929-1932 (Box 3, Folder 115-117)
    - Talks and Addresses Given by Members of Staff, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Yakoviev Article, undated (Box 3, Folder 119)